Finding Aid for the J. Paul Getty Trust Inventory of Getty Publications, 1954-2013 and undated IA10020
Institutional Records and Archives
Inventory of Getty publications
1954-2013
Institutional Records and Archives
J. Paul Getty Trust
Getty Information Institute
J. Paul Getty Museum
Getty Research Institute
Getty Art History Information Program
Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities
Getty Center for Education in the Arts
IA10020
74.8 Linear Feet (114 boxes)
The materials include publications issued by the J. Paul Getty Trust or Getty Publications, including titles published by, or on behalf of, the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Getty Conservation Institute, the Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities, the Getty Research Institute, the Project for Art on Film, the Getty Art History Information Program, the Getty Information Institute, and the Getty Center for Education in the Arts, dating from 1954 to 2012. The materials include museum guides, exhibition catalogues, art books, information on the conservation of art and historical sites, conference notes, J. Paul Getty Trust annual reports, art history resource guides, and material related to arts in education.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series:
Series I. J. Paul Getty Museum, 1954-2013, undated
Series II. Getty Conservation Institute (GCI), 1974-2013
Series III. Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities (GCHAH) and Getty Research Institute (GRI), 1985-2013, undated
Series IV. Project for Art on Film, 1993
Series V. Getty Art History Information Program and Getty Information Institute, 1984-1999, undated
Series VI. Getty Center for Education in the Arts (GCEA), 1984-2003, undated
Series VII. Other, 1997, 1998, 2001.
Scope and Contents of Collection
The materials comprise publications, dating from 1954 to 2012, issued by the J. Paul Getty Trust or Getty Publications. Materials were published by or on behalf of the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Getty Conservation Institute, the Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities and the Getty Research Institute, the Project for Art on Film, the Getty Art History Information Program and Getty Information Institute, and the Getty Center for Education in the Arts. The materials include museum guides, exhibition catalogues, art books, information on the conservation of art and historical sites, conference notes, J. Paul Getty Trust annual reports, art history resource guides, and material related to arts in education.
The J. Paul Getty Museum publications contain museum guides, issues of the museum journal, exhibition catalogues and art books. The publications from the Getty Conservation Institute contain reports on conservation projects and processes. Publications from the Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities and the Getty Research Institute contain J. Paul Getty Trust reports and arts books. The Getty Art History Information Program and Getty Information Institute publications contain information about art and technology and art reference books. The publications from the Getty Center for Education in the Arts contain conference and seminar proceedings and information on the role art plays in education and how to enhance this role.
These materials represent publications that have been donated or transferred to the Institutional Archives periodically over the years. There are gaps in the holdings; this is not a comprehensive collection of Getty publications. Select publications are available online (full text) at the Getty's virtual library: https://www.getty.edu/publications/virtuallibrary
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials described in this finding aid originated in accessions 1987.IA.04, 2005.IA.16, 2006.IA.01, 2007.IA.01, 2008.IA.01, 2009.IA.01, 2010.IA.01, 2011.IA.01, 2012.IA.01, and 2013.IA.01. The materials were transferred periodically from Getty Publications to the Institutional Archives.
Access Restrictions
The records described in accessions 1987.IA.04, 2005.IA.16, 2006.IA.01, 2007.IA.01, 2008.IA.01, 2009.IA.01, 2010.IA.01, 2011.IA.01, and 2012.IA.01 are available for use by qualified researchers. Select publications are available online (full text) at the Getty's virtual library: https://www.getty.edu/publications/virtuallibrary
The following types of records are permanently closed: records containing personal information, records that compromise security or operations, legal communications, legal work product, and records related to donors. The J. Paul Getty Trust reserves the right to restrict access to any records held by the Institutional Archives.
Administrative History
The J. Paul Getty Trust is a not-for-profit institution, educational in purpose and character, that focuses on the visual arts in all of their dimensions. As of 2013 the Trust supports and oversees four programs: the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Getty Foundation, the Getty Conservation Institute, and the Getty Research Institute. The J. Paul Getty Trust and Getty programs serve a varied audience from two locations: the Getty Center in Los Angeles and the Getty Villa near Malibu, California.
The origins of the J. Paul Getty Trust date to 1953, when J. Paul Getty established the J. Paul Getty Museum as a California charitable trust to house his growing art collections. Originally a small, private institution located in Mr. Getty's ranch house near Malibu, the museum moved to the newly-constructed Getty Villa in grounds adjacent to the ranch house in 1974. When most of Mr. Getty's personal estate passed to the Trust in 1982, the Trustees decided that, given the size of the endowment, it should make a greater contribution to the visual arts and humanities than the museum could alone. Out of this resolve grew an expanded commitment to the arts in the areas of scholarship, conservation, and education. This took the shape of new programs including the Center for the History of Arts and Humanities, Art History Information Institute, Conservation Institute, and Center for Education in the Arts, as well as smaller programs such as the Museum Management Institute and the Program for Art on Film. In 1983 the Trust's name was changed from the J. Paul Getty Museum to the J. Paul Getty Trust to reflect its broader scope, with the Museum becoming an operating program of the Trust.
Due to expanded operations and limited space at the original J. Paul Getty Museum in Pacific Palisades, near Malibu, the various programs of the J. Paul Getty Trust were located at different sites throughout the Los Angeles basin during the 1980s and early 1990s. The Trust's vision was to bring together most of their programs at a single site. A roughly 750-acre property in Brentwood (west Los Angeles) was purchased by the Trust in 1983 and the Getty Center was built to house the Trust, its newly created programs, and an additional space for the Museum. While the Getty's collection of antiquities remained at the Villa, the rest of the collections were moved to the new and much larger facility at the Center.
The Publications office / department was originally established as part of the Museum and is frequently referred to as "Getty Publications." With the founding of the Trust in 1983, the Publications department became responsible for the publications produced by the J. Paul Getty Trust and its operating programs. Since then Publications has undergone considerable restructuring. Over the years the administration of the Publications department has shifted back and forth several times between the Museum and the Trust, and at times there have been separate publications departments within various Getty programs. In recent years Publications' primary focus has been the editing, design, production, and marketing of exhibition catalogs and books for the J. Paul Getty Museum, Getty Conservation Institute, and Getty Research Institute, including books on art, photography, art history, and children's literature. Historically Publications has also produced a wider variety of materials, including Trust reports and ephemera such as event invitations, newsletters, informational brochures, site and gallery maps, and other visitor handouts.
Art -- History; Museum publications; Art in education; Art -- Conservation and restoration; Historic sites -- Conservation and restoration; Exhibition catalogs; Publications; Getty Conservation Institute; J. Paul Getty Museum
- J. Paul Getty Museum, 1954-2000; 2003-2013,; undated; Series I.
  Administrative History
  The J. Paul Getty Museum was established as a charitable trust in 1953 by J. Paul Getty in order to house his growing art collections. The museum and its collections grew relatively slowly, finally moving from rooms in Getty's Malibu ranch house into the newly-constructed Villa museum in 1974.
  Though J. Paul Getty bequeathed the majority of his estate to the museum upon his death in 1976, these assets remained unavailable until 1983. Harold M. Williams was hired as President of the Trust in 1981 and, with the Board of Trustees, created a plan to expand the Trust's range of activities in order to fully utilize the new endowment and to strengthen the entire organization's responsibilities to the arts world. As a part of its expansion program, the Trust planned and built the Getty Center campus in Brentwood, which opened in 1997. While the Getty's collection of antiquities remained at the Villa, the rest of the collections were moved to the new and much larger facility at the Center.
  Scope and Contents
  Material comprises Getty publications by or about the J. Paul Getty Museum and its collections or activities.
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Valentiner, W.R. and Paul Wescher. The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook. Los Angeles: 1954., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Valentiner, W.R. and Paul Wescher. The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook. Los Angeles: 1956. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Bulletin of the J. Paul Getty Museum of Art, Volume 1 Number 1. Malibu: 1957., (4 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Bulletin of the J. Paul Getty Museum of Art, Volume 1 Number 2. Malibu: 1959. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Getty, J. Paul. The Joys of Collecting. New York: 1965. (Box 2010.IA.01-03)
  - Jones, Anne Marian. A Handbook of the Decorative Arts in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1965. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Stothart, Herbert. A Handbook of the Sculpture in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1965. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. and Darrell D. Davisson. Benvenuto Di Giovanni, Girolamo Di Benvenuto: Their Altarpieces in the J. Paul Getty Museum. And a Summary Catalogue of Their Paintings in America. Malibu: 1966., (3 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
    General
    Series: Publication No. 2.
  - Howard, Seymour. The Lansdowne Herakles. Malibu: 1966. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
    Series: Publication No. 1.
  - Bieber, Margarete. The Statue of Cybele in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1968. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
    Series: Publication No. 3.
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. The Cassone Paintings of Francesco Di Giorgio. Malibu: 1969., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
    Series: Publication No. 4.
  - Selected Works from the Ancient Art Collection of the John Paul Getty Museum, Malibu, California, [Catalog of the exhibition] May 29-June 20, June 28-July 10, 1971, Hetzel Union Gallery: A Pennsylvania State University College of Art and Architecture Exhibition. University Park: 1971., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. Catalogue of the Paintings in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1972., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Frederickson, Burton B., and Federico Zeri. Census of Pre-Nineteenth-Century Italian Paintings in North American Public Collections. Cambridge, MA: 1972. (Box 2010.IA.01-02)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts. The J. Paul Getty Collection: A Minneapolis Institute of Arts Exhibition. Catalog of an Exhibition held June 29-Sept. 3, 1972. Minneapolis: 1972., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Wilson, Gillian. Boulle. 1972. (Box 2010.IA.01-02)
    This likely was originally an article in Furniture History magazine (the journal of the Furniture History Society), 1972 issue (published annually). The FHS webpage has the author as "Gillian Watson."
  - Baroque Masters from the J. Paul Getty Museum. A California State University, Northridge Exhibition, February 26 1973 - March 30 1973. Northridge: 1973., (Copy 1 of 2) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Baroque Masters from the J. Paul Getty Museum. A California State University, Northridge Exhibition, February 26 1973 - March 30 1973. Northridge: 1973., (Copy 2 of 2) (Box 2012.IA.01-12)
  - Fehm Jr., Sherwood A. The Collaboration of Niccolo Tegliacci and Luca Di Tomme. Los Angeles: 1973., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Greek and Roman Portraits from the J. Paul Getty Museum. A California State University, Northridge Exhibition, October 16, 1973 - November 11, 1973. Northridge: 1973. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Vermeule, Cornelius and Norman Neuerburg. Catalogue of the Ancient Art in the J. Paul Getty Museum, The Larger Statuary, Wall Paintings and Mosaics. Malibu: 1973., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Buckley, Elizabeth. The Roman Gardens at the J. Paul Getty Museum, Brochure No. 3. Malibu: 1974. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Buckley, Penny. The Splendors of Ancient Rome: a Seventeenth Century View. Malibu: 1974. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. Giovanni Di Francesco and the Master of Pratovecchio. Malibu: 1974., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
    Series: Publication No. 6.
  - Frel, Jiří, ed. The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal, Volume 1. Malibu: 1974. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Gebhard, David. Getty's Museum: Is it Disgusting and Downright Outrageous. Reprinted from Architecture Plus. 1974 (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Recent Acquisitions of Ancient Art from the J. Paul Getty Museum. A Washington State University Exhibition, October 9, 1974 - October 30, 1974. Pullman, WA: 1974. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Stead, Rexford. The Ardabil Carpets. Los Angeles: 1974., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - A Temporary Guide to the J. Paul Getty Museum for the Assistance of Visitors During the Period Immediately After the Opening of the New Museum. Malibu: 1974., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Cristin, Lilli, ed.The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook. Malibu: 1975, (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., ed.The J. Paul Getty Museum: Greek and Roman Antiquities, Western European Paintings, French Decorative Arts of the Eighteenth Century. London: 1975., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Frel, Jiří, ed.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 2. Malibu: 1975. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Neuerburg, Norman. Herculaneum to Malibu: A Companion to the Visit of the J. Paul Getty Museum Building. Malibu: 1975., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Rinne, David and Jiří Frel. The Bronze Statue of a Youth: An Account of the Recreation of an Ancient Statue. Malibu: 1975., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Rubin, Helen. Marie Cieri, Karen Saunders, and Laurie Slater, eds. Honore Daumier: Histoire Ancienne. [exhibition] May 1-June 15, 1975 / presented by the University of Southern California Fine Arts Department at the J. Paul Getty Museum, Malibu. Los Angeles: 1975. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Armstrong, Roberta, Margaret Breslin, Henry Grosshans, eds. Rodin: The Maryhill Collection: Bronzes, Plasters, and Watercolors. A Washington State University Exhibition, February 4, 1976 - February 29, 1976. Pullman, WA: 1976. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Armstrong, Roberta, Margaret Breslin, Henry Grosshans, eds. Rodin: The Maryhill Collection: Bronzes, Plasters, and Watercolors. A Washington State University Exhibition, February 4, 1976 - February 29, 1976. Pullman, WA: 1976. (Box 2008.IA.01-03)
  - Ashin, Deborah. The Herb in Antiquity: A Look into the J. Paul Getty Museum Herb Garden. Malibu: 1976. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Cristin, Lilli, ed. The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook. Malibu: 1976., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. Alma Tadema's Spring. Malibu: 1976. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Fredericksen, Burton, ed.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 3. Malibu: 1976. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Frel, Jiří and Selma Holo. South Italian Vases, An Exhibition at the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1976. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum. Recent Acquisitions of Antiquities: June 1-September 3, 1976, Special Exhibits Room 123. Malibu: 1976. (Box 2010.IA.01-02)
  - Kingsley, Bonnie M. The Terracottas of the Tarantine Greeks. Malibu: 1976., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
    Series: Publication No. 8.
  - Rinne, David. The Conservation of Ancient Marble. Malibu: 1976., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Thompson, David L. The Artists of the Mummy Portraits. Malibu: 1976. (Box 2008.IA.01-03)
    Series: Publication No. 7.
  - Thompson, David L. The Artists of the Mummy Portraits. Malibu: 1976. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - Wilson, Gillian. Clocks: French Eighteenth Century Clocks in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1976., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 2)
  - The Armand Hammer Collection at the J. Paul Getty Museum: September 13, 1977 - October 19, 1977. Malibu: 1977. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Ashin, Deborah and Wanda Chin. Discovery Tour of the J. Paul Getty Museum: A Guidebook for Children and Friends of All Ages. Malibu: 1977. (Box 2010.IA.01-02)
  - Breslin, Joseph. A Greek Prayer: the Translation and Account of a Short Burial Prayer Engraved by an Ancient People on a Tiny Sheet of Gold and Found Among the Ashes in a Cinerary Urn. Pasadena: 1977., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 1)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. and Richard J. Kubiak. Etchings of Rembrandt and His Followers: A Selection from the Robert Engel Family Collection. Malibu, Santa Barbara: 1977. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum Pamphlet One. Malibu: 1977., (3 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum Pamphlet Two. Malibu: 1977 (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Greek Vases in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1977 (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Wilson, Gillian, ed.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 4. Malibu: 1977. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří, ed.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 5: 1977. Malibu: 1978. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Wilson, Gillian. Decorative Arts in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1977., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Wilson, Gillian. Royal Decorative Arts in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1977. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. Alma Tadema's Spring, Revised Edition. Malibu: 1978., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. The Getty Bronze. Malibu: 1978., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
    Series: Publication No. 9.
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum Pamphlet 3: Conservation of Antiquities. Malibu: 1978., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum Pamphlet 4: The Getty Bronze. Malibu: 1978. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum Pamphlet 5: Euphronios in Malibu. Malibu: 1978., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Howard, Seymour. The Lansdowne Herakles, Revised Edition. Malibu: 1978., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum 1979 Appointment Calendar. Los Angeles: 1978. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - Morgan, Sandra, ed. The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook Fourth Edition. Malibu: 1978., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Treasures of the Ancients: A Selection of Greek Vases from the J. Paul Getty Museum: an Exhibition at the University of California, Riverside, June 12 through August 5, 1978. Riverside: 1978. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., Jiří Frel, and Gillian Wilson, eds.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 6/7, 1978-1979. Malibu: 1979. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum: A Checklist Sculpture 1. Greek Originals. Malibu: 1979. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Frel, Jiří. Antiquities in the J. Paul Getty Museum: A Checklist Sculpture 2. Greek Portraits and Varia. Malibu: 1979., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum 1980 Appointment Calendar. Los Angeles: 1979. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum Address Book. Los Angeles: 1979. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - Painting on Vases in Ancient Greece. A Loyola Marymount University Exhibition. Los Angeles: March 20, 1979 - April 22, 1979. Los Angeles: 1979., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 3)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B. Masterpieces of Painting in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1980., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., Jiří Frel, and Gillian Wilson, eds.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 8, 1980. Malibu: 1980. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum 1981 Appointment Calendar. Los Angeles: 1980. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum 1981 Appointment Calendar. Los Angeles: 1980. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - Jentoft-Nilsen, Marit. Ancient Portraiture: The Sculptor's Art in Coins and Marble: a Loan Exhibition on Display at the Virginia Museum, April 29 to July 20, 1980. Richmond, VA: 1980. (Box 2010.IA.01-02)
  - Roman Portraits: Aspects of Self and Society, First Century B.C.-Third Century A.D.: a loan exhibition. A Loyola Marymount University and University of California, Santa Cruz Exhibition. Los Angeles and Santa Cruz: 1980., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - Rubsamen, Gisela, ed. The Orsini Inventories. Malibu: 1980., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
    Series: JPGM archival series; no. 1.
  - Stamnoi, An Exhibition at the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1980., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - Wilson, Gillian, Burton Fredericksen, and Jiří Frel, eds.The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook Fifth Edition. Malibu: 1980. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - Decorative Arts Address Book. Los Angeles: 1981. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., Jiří Frel, and Gillian Wilson, eds.The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 9/1981. Malibu: 1981. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - Frel, Jiří. Greek Portraits in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1981., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - Frel, Jiří. Roman Portraits in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1981., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum 1982 Appointment Calendar. Los Angeles: 1981. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum Coloring Book. Santa Barbara: 1981. (Box 2010.IA.01-02)
  - Vermeule, Cornelius C. Greek and Roman Sculpture in America: Masterpieces in Public Collections in the United States and Canada. Berkley, Los Angeles, London: 1981., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 4)
  - D'Andrea, Jeanne. Ancient Herbs in the J. Paul Getty Museum Garden. Malibu: 1982. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - Frel, Jiří. The Getty Bronze Revised Edition. Malibu: 1982., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum Brochure. Malibu: 1982. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - The J. Paul Getty Museum 1983 Appointment Calendar. Los Angeles: 1982. (Box 2010.IA.01-12)
  - Stewart, Andrew. Skopas in Malibu: The Head of Achilles from Tegea and Other Sculptures by Skopas in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1982., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - Thompson, David L. Mummy Portraits in the J. Paul Getty Museum, Revised. Malibu: 1982. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - Watson, F.J.B. and Wilson, Gillian. Mounted Oriental Porcelain in the J. Paul Getty Museum. Malibu: 1982., (4 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - Wilson, Gillian, Burton Fredericksen, and Jiří Frel, eds. The J. Paul Getty Museum Guidebook Sixth Edition. Malibu: 1982. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - Wilson, Gillian, Burton Fredericksen, and Jiří Frel, eds. The J. Paul Getty Museum Journal Volume 10/1982. Malibu: 1982., (3 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 5)
  - Chamy, Jacques, Jiří Frel, and Jean-Louis Maier. Le Monde des Cesars: Portraits Romains. Geneve: 1983. (Box 2010.IA.01-04)